<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fatima Ghadieh</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://fjg00.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Fatima Ghadieh</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://fjg00.github.io/media/icon_hu9858ce0c41cff0f516960af2e343a3e7_237784_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Fatima Ghadieh</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/</link></image><item><title>Example Talk</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/talk/example-talk/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/talk/example-talk/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert alert-note">
&lt;div>
Click on the &lt;strong>Slides&lt;/strong> button above to view the built-in slides feature.
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Create&lt;/strong> slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&lt;em>Slides&lt;/em>&lt;/a> feature and link using &lt;code>slides&lt;/code> parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Upload&lt;/strong> an existing slide deck to &lt;code>static/&lt;/code> and link using &lt;code>url_slides&lt;/code> parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Embed&lt;/strong> your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shortcodes&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Further event details, including &lt;a href="https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">page elements&lt;/a> such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Policy Evaluation in Decentralized POMDPs with Belief Sharing</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/publication/decpompd_epfl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/publication/decpompd_epfl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>IDEAS 2023</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/ideas2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/ideas2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>My final year project team and I had the pleasure of participating in IDEAS 2023, a flagship spring event at the American University of Beirut that showcases research being conducted at its faculty of engineering. We presented our final year project findings to faculty and students, and were one of the few teams that were nominated for the &amp;ldquo;Creative Achievement Award&amp;rdquo;. It was an excellent networking opportunity that allowed us to showcase the value of our project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LEBNet EIC Scholarship</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/lebnet_eic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/lebnet_eic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Absolutely thrilled to have received the LEBNet Scholarship Award for the year 2023, an award intended for senior Lebanese engineering students from different Lebanese universities planning to pursue their graduate studies in the U.S. or Canada. The LebNet scholarship is a testament to their unwavering support and belief in my potential, and it has given me the motivation and drive to continue striving for excellence in my studies and future endeavors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am deeply grateful for this opportunity, and I am committed to making the most of it by working diligently and contributing positively to the LebNet community.
In addition to the scholarship award, I will also be teamed up with a LebNet mentor from the Early in Career community who would be willing to provide guidance and support throughout my academic journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Switzerland 2022</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/travelphotos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/travelphotos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reflecting on my summer 2022 as I begin summer 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excellence in Engineering Fellowship at EPFL, Switzerland</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/asl_epfl2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/asl_epfl2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel honored to have had the opportunity to spend my summer as a research intern at the Adaptive Systems lab at EPFL. The experience was truly incredible and surpassed all my expectations. Not only did I have the chance to work on a high-caliber project, but I also had the opportunity to explore and travel throughout Switzerland, immersing myself in the rich culture and diverse languages of the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EPFL&amp;rsquo;s faculty and staff were exceptionally friendly and welcoming, creating a supportive and collaborative environment. The work-life balance at EPFL was impressive, allowing me to make the most of my time both inside and outside the lab. I had the privilege of visiting numerous breathtaking locations such as Zermatt, Gruyeres, Zurich, Bern, Noiraigue, Lugano, Bellinzona, Nyon, and even the renowned CERN in Geneva.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout my internship, I was fortunate to work alongside my mentor and advisor, Mr. Kayaalp. His mentorship was truly admirable, and I consider myself lucky to have been one of his first students in his PhD journey. Together, we achieved great results, culminating in the publication of a journal paper. This accomplishment has been a testament to the dedication and guidance provided by Mr. Kayaalp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The EPFL campus itself is nothing short of amazing. Surrounded by the majestic Alps, the combination of the stunning natural beauty and the presence of world-class faculty inspires the mind and fuels creativity. Every day on campus was a source of motivation and excitement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, my summer at the Adaptive Systems lab at EPFL has been a transformative experience. I am immensely grateful for the opportunity to work on cutting-edge research, explore Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s beauty, and forge lifelong friendships. It is an experience that will undoubtedly shape my academic and personal journey for years to come.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AUBot, A Chatbot for University FAQs</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/project/aubot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/project/aubot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Driver safety is a major concern for the automotive industry today, and researchers and industries are exploring the introduction of self-driving vehicles as a solution. These vehicles aim to assist drivers during their journeys, making them more enjoyable, safe, and efficient. Despite the introduction of new features to self-driving vehicles, many people still do not trust them enough and prefer to be in control of the driving experience. This lack of trust can be attributed to various factors, such as the lack of information about automated vehicles, poor communication with the automation, or people being unaware of the full capabilities of the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address this issue, we propose a human-machine interface (HMI) that facilitates the process of hand-back and takeover between the driver and the vehicle. Our HMI leverages inputs from the Controller Area Network (CAN) bus of the car to predict the driver&amp;rsquo;s intentions accurately and display them in a safe and user-friendly manner. We evaluated several predictions, such as identifying whether the driver is stuck in traffic or attempting to parallel-park.
As our project involves the safety of drivers and passengers, we must comply with several standards and constraints. Our system must make accurate predictions in real-time while running on a local device, adhering to various standards set by associations such as SAE, NHTSA, and ITU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We used the CARLA (Car Learning to Act) Simulator to simulate real-world traffic scenarios and parallel parking situations, collecting data such as throttle, brake, speed, steering wheel angle, and reverse signals for analysis. This analysis enabled us to develop and test various machine learning models, ultimately choosing the models with the highest accuracy. We then designed an HMI that adheres to the relevant standards and effectively communicates the predictions to the driver. We conducted experiments on the CARLA Simulator and administered a questionnaire to assess the performance of the HMI and the predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Facebook Group Post Scraper</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/project/facebookgroup_scraper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/project/facebookgroup_scraper/</guid><description>&lt;p>Driver safety&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shared Control for Autonomous Driving</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/project/sharedcontrol_fyp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/project/sharedcontrol_fyp/</guid><description>&lt;p>Driver safety is a major concern for the automotive industry today, and researchers and industries are exploring the introduction of self-driving vehicles as a solution. These vehicles aim to assist drivers during their journeys, making them more enjoyable, safe, and efficient. Despite the introduction of new features to self-driving vehicles, many people still do not trust them enough and prefer to be in control of the driving experience. This lack of trust can be attributed to various factors, such as the lack of information about automated vehicles, poor communication with the automation, or people being unaware of the full capabilities of the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To address this issue, we propose a human-machine interface (HMI) that facilitates the process of hand-back and takeover between the driver and the vehicle. Our HMI leverages inputs from the Controller Area Network (CAN) bus of the car to predict the driver&amp;rsquo;s intentions accurately and display them in a safe and user-friendly manner. We evaluated several predictions, such as identifying whether the driver is stuck in traffic or attempting to parallel-park.
As our project involves the safety of drivers and passengers, we must comply with several standards and constraints. Our system must make accurate predictions in real-time while running on a local device, adhering to various standards set by associations such as SAE, NHTSA, and ITU.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We used the CARLA (Car Learning to Act) Simulator to simulate real-world traffic scenarios and parallel parking situations, collecting data such as throttle, brake, speed, steering wheel angle, and reverse signals for analysis. This analysis enabled us to develop and test various machine learning models, ultimately choosing the models with the highest accuracy. We then designed an HMI that adheres to the relevant standards and effectively communicates the predictions to the driver. We conducted experiments on the CARLA Simulator and administered a questionnaire to assess the performance of the HMI and the predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://fjg00.github.io/admin/config.yml</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://fjg00.github.io/talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/talk/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>https://fjg00.github.io/slides/example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/slides/example/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>