<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal | Fatima Ghadieh</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/tag/personal/</link><atom:link href="https://fjg00.github.io/tag/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Personal</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://fjg00.github.io/media/icon_hu9858ce0c41cff0f516960af2e343a3e7_237784_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Personal</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/tag/personal/</link></image><item><title>Note as I End my Journey at AUB</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/aub_journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/aub_journey/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="reflecting-on-my-time-at-aub-to-be-filled-by-the-time-i-graduate">Reflecting on my time at AUB, to be filled by the time I graduate.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As closing time approaches, I want to look back at my journey throughout AUB as an undergraduate student, and really think about everything that happened. Starting as an anxious little child, already scared of failing my courses as I take my first steps into AUB campus, and really transforming into a person who has grown fond of their experience at AUB, indulging in every little step, and immersing my self in new memories, experiences, and of course, projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of my biggest regrets was that I did not involve myself in university life as much as I could have. It took me a lot of time to break out of my shell as a shy person. While I do consider to have had my fair share of &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; or rather &amp;ldquo;colleagues&amp;rdquo; during my first two years of university, I did spend a lot of time inside the library and practically avoided interactions with anyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The courses I took during my first year were quite heavy and required a lot of studying day-by-day. The most memorable courses that I havve thorouhgly enjoyed, and which really got me excited for pursuing this degree was EECE 210 with professor Fadi Karameh. My classmates were absolutely amazing and friendly people who later became one of my greatest friends throughout my journey at AUB. what I have especially learned is that the firneds and community you surround yourself with realy affects your attitude towards practically anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then came covid, which resulted in spending a year and a half online, destroying my mental health, allowing me to overwork myself with the free-time I had. While being stuck in my room for over 10 hours was a very nerve-wracking experience, I do think that it had its benefits in terms of really allowing me to understand the material fully and get a firm grip of the courses I took. I also took quite heavy courses to take advantage of the online experience. Alot of my friendships were made online, becaus eat that time we had started to be tasked with projects which require d us working in groupps. It was such a weird and surreal experience meeting peope who were practically your best friends for the first time in person.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, at that point in time, and as I started my third year at AUB, I was very nsure about what I was going to do with my life, I was extremely anxious about internship season. Setup my linkedIn account, started taking those online courses on coursera, and just trying as much as I can to stand out from students who were also applying. I also had taken part in assisting Professor loua Bazzi in preaprig EECE 230X, a transformative course that would later be offered by AUB in an online format which provides an introduction to programming. The aim of this course is to make knowledge in coding much more accessible in the arb world. At the beginning, I helped translate those videos into arabic, whlile also adding captions in english. Fol Then I also assisted in fixing audio issues within the videos. After that,a nd once the course was ready to be published I took on the role of the data analyst within a team of 14 students. think this experienc eby far wa one of the most beneficial experiences I have been throughas a student at AUB. i tried my best to prove myself , not ust for everyone, but also for me. it was such a rewarding experience, it required a lot of responsibility, effort, and time, but it was all worth it. I helped manage the team of students, I tracked the progress of all stuents taking the course, checking their levels of interaction with the material, monitoring their attendances, listening to feedback from the coding coaches, compiling everything and making weekly reports that summarize all findings per week. Those reports allowed us to really form the foundation of educated decision-making based on course statistics. The course was a great success, both on a residential level within AUB, and for the open access oferring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following that, I had the orevilige of interviewing people who took this course, listening to their feedback, and reporting all findings t the professor. Listening to the impact of this intiative on the students lives really affected me personally, because it made me realize how our efforts have really culimnated into such great results&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>