<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts | Fatima Ghadieh</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/</link><atom:link href="https://fjg00.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Posts</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://fjg00.github.io/media/icon_hu9858ce0c41cff0f516960af2e343a3e7_237784_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Posts</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/</link></image><item><title>IDEAS 2023</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/ideas2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/ideas2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>My final year project team and I had the pleasure of participating in IDEAS 2023, a flagship spring event at the American University of Beirut that showcases research being conducted at its faculty of engineering. We presented our final year project findings to faculty and students, and were one of the few teams that were nominated for the &amp;ldquo;Creative Achievement Award&amp;rdquo;. It was an excellent networking opportunity that allowed us to showcase the value of our project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>LEBNet EIC Scholarship</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/lebnet_eic/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/lebnet_eic/</guid><description>&lt;p>Absolutely thrilled to have received the LEBNet Scholarship Award for the year 2023, an award intended for senior Lebanese engineering students from different Lebanese universities planning to pursue their graduate studies in the U.S. or Canada. The LebNet scholarship is a testament to their unwavering support and belief in my potential, and it has given me the motivation and drive to continue striving for excellence in my studies and future endeavors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am deeply grateful for this opportunity, and I am committed to making the most of it by working diligently and contributing positively to the LebNet community.
In addition to the scholarship award, I will also be teamed up with a LebNet mentor from the Early in Career community who would be willing to provide guidance and support throughout my academic journey.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Switzerland 2022</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/travelphotos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/travelphotos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reflecting on my summer 2022 as I begin summer 2023.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Excellence in Engineering Fellowship at EPFL, Switzerland</title><link>https://fjg00.github.io/post/asl_epfl2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://fjg00.github.io/post/asl_epfl2022/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="my-experience-at-epfl-as-a-research-intern">My Experience at EPFL as a Research Intern&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I feel honored to have had the opportunity to spend my summer as a research intern at the Adaptive Systems lab at EPFL. The experience was truly incredible and surpassed all my expectations. Not only did I have the chance to work on a high-caliber project, but I also had the opportunity to explore and travel throughout Switzerland, immersing myself in the rich culture and diverse languages of the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>EPFL&amp;rsquo;s faculty and staff were exceptionally friendly and welcoming, creating a supportive and collaborative environment. The work-life balance at EPFL was impressive, allowing me to make the most of my time both inside and outside the lab. I had the privilege of visiting numerous breathtaking locations such as Zermatt, Gruyeres, Zurich, Bern, Noiraigue, Lugano, Bellinzona, Nyon, and even the renowned CERN in Geneva.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout my internship, I was fortunate to work alongside my mentor and advisor, Mr. Kayaalp. His mentorship was truly admirable, and I consider myself lucky to have been one of his first students in his PhD journey. Together, we achieved great results, culminating in the publication of a journal paper. This accomplishment has been a testament to the dedication and guidance provided by Mr. Kayaalp.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The EPFL campus itself is nothing short of amazing. Surrounded by the majestic Alps, the combination of the stunning natural beauty and the presence of world-class faculty inspires the mind and fuels creativity. Every day on campus was a source of motivation and excitement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, my summer at the Adaptive Systems lab at EPFL has been a transformative experience. I am immensely grateful for the opportunity to work on cutting-edge research, explore Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s beauty, and form lifelong friendships. It is an experience that will undoubtedly shape my academic and personal journey for years to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="my-research-project-an-in-depth-look">My Research Project: An In-depth look&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Policy Evaluation in Decentralized POMDPs with Belief Sharing&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>